最後    一關
按開始按鈕
第139次嘗試
起床 抬頭
Wakey Wakey. Heads up!
穿鞋 穿褲子…彎腰 T恤
Shoes, pants... Low bridge! Shirt...
左側襲來 刀我收下了
On your left. I'll take that.
擋一招 拍一招 他的刀換手
Block, slap. Knife switch.
扭住他 翻他個狗吃屎
Grip him, flip him.
好了 能喝杯咖啡了嗎
Okay. Coffee anyone?
你能想像每天醒來
Can you imagine waking up every day
都有一個不知道哪裡來的混蛋
with some random asshole like Mr Good Morning here
想用一把操蛋的砍刀來砍你
trying to hack you up with a fucking machete.
真的假的
Seriously.
看來得有一陣子好玩了
This might have been fun for a while.
你死定了
You're fuckin' dead!
一旦震盪平息
Once the shock wore off,
一旦我意識到了究竟發生了什麼
once I realised what the hell was happening,
差不多一百四十次了
after nearly a hundred and forty times
這真的很煩人
it just fuckin' got annoying.
我想要這一切停下來
And I want it to stop.
但我知道不可能
But I know it won't.
你知道有些人會吹牛 說什麼“我閉著眼都能做到”之類的
You know how people say say, "Oh, I can do that with my eyes closed",
這他媽都是些屁話
and you always think they sound like assholes
不過…
But... whatever.
看我的
Watch.
抱歉 夥計 他們把你錯當成我了
I'm sorry, pal, they've mistaken you for me.
每次看到我的公寓裡發生這種事 我就想
As many times as I've seen this happen to my apartment, I still can't help but think:
該死 這房子是租來的
"Fuck, man this is a lease..."
房東本來就是個混蛋
The landlord is already an asshole anyway and...
我的押金肯定是拿不回來了
I'm never ever getting my security deposit back.
事情並不總是這樣
It wasn't always like this.
我以前很幸福 真的
I was happy once. I really was.
我曾經有一個深愛的女人
I had a woman that I loved
但如今我是真的搞砸了
but now I'm just pissed off.
臥槽 我還得跳樓
Ah shit, gotta jump.
之前的輪回裡我有22次錯過了這輛卡車
I missed this truck exactly twenty two times before
你知道從四樓窗戶掉下來是什麼感覺嗎
Know how it feels, falling four storeys to the street below?
真他媽的疼
It fuckin' hurts is how it feels.
在這輛道奇車裡的那個人每次總是大喊大叫
Mr Man's Man in the challenger here screams at date-rape volume every single time
-有人要搶我的車！ -大實話 沒毛病
- I'm being car-jacked! - Yes, you are.
另一批想要殺我的混蛋坐在那輛小車裡
The next set of assholes trying to kill me are in that minivan.
-你來開這段路行不行 -不用你來教我開車
- Could you get through this traffic, please? - Don't tell me how to drive.
-我不是在教你 -司機是埃斯梅拉達 另一個是帕姆
- I'm not telling you how to drive. - Esmeralda the chauffeur and Pam.
我不知道他們的真名叫什麼
I have no fuckin' idea if those are their real names because
反正也沒有時間打招呼
I never stop to say hello.
經歷公車之後就爽歪歪了我可以……
Now, after the bus it's pretty much smooth sailing and I can...
等等 我已經遇上公車了嗎
Wait a second, did I... Oh shit, did I get to the bus yet?
不
Nope
看在上帝的份上
God?
別擔心我
Don't feel bad for me.
這些破事每天都會發生
This kinda shit happens every day.
我以前總是抱怨 因為每天看起來都一個樣
I used to complain that every day it felt the same.
然後是5月9日
And then May 9th came
如今每天都一模一樣了
and now every day is the same.
每次你一尖叫 就有同一個拿著砍刀的混蛋出現
The same wake-up scream, the same machete-wielding asshole.
一切都一樣，只是略有不同
The same everything, with slight variations.
真他媽的
Motherf... Agh!
只有一件事永遠不會改變
One thing that never changes.
每一天
Is I die.
我都會死
Every single day.
我又死了
I die.
這裡有一點要注意一下
Here's a little highlight reel.
說句實話
Now, truth be told
我完全不知道他們為什麼要殺我
I don't even know why they want to kill me
難道是我罪有應得 屎話屎說
or what I've done to deserve getting killed, but there's a shit-tonne of 'em.
你們已經認識帕姆了
You've met Pam.
在我終於找到絕佳的降落時機前 她幹掉了我十四次
She did that to me fourteen times before I finally got the timing down.
這個天屎傻逼就是觀音
This little angel-faced asshole is known as Guan-Jin.
她的名字我是怎麼知道的呢
How do I know her name?
我叫觀音
I am Guan-Jin!
觀音完成任務
And Guan-Jin has done this.
她的名字的意思是慈悲女神
Her name means Goddess of Mercy.
相當諷刺不是嗎
I think she digs irony.
這個矮個子我叫他卡布姆
I call this cocky little motherfucker Kaboom.
-你好呀 帥哥
What's up pretty boy?
你他媽在幹啥 矮冬瓜？
You fuckin' weird old dwarf, what are you doing?
我不喜歡你這個態度
Oh, I don't like that attitude.
我給他們都起了外號 帕姆 笑臉
I gave them all nicknames: Pam, Smiley,
德國雙胞胎 羅伊2號
the German twins, Roy number 2,
是個碰巧長得跟我一模一樣的混蛋
Who just happens tobe some asshole who looks exactly like me.
有時候我能殺掉他們
Sometimes I manage to kill them.
但這不是重點
But it doesn't matter.
他們總會找到我最後幹掉我
They always find me and eventually they take me out.
我是觀音
I'm Guan-Jin!
觀音完成任務
And Guan-Jin has done this.
我不明白這是怎麼回事 為什麼我總是在重複同樣的一天
I don't know how this is possible, or why I keep repeating the same day.
我也沒有時間去查明
I've never had time to figure it out
自從我睜開眼 一切就瘋狂了起來
It's a shit show from the second I open my eyes.
正在進行中
傑瑪 我唯一愛的女人
Jemma, the only woman I've ever loved,
唯一一個知道我要找尋的答案的人
and the one person who has the answers I'm looking for.
-你好 -我要找傑瑪威爾斯博士
- Hello? - Uh... I'm looking for Dr. Jemma Wells.
你是誰
Who's this?
我是她丈...她男朋友 羅伊
This is her husb... her boyfriend Roy.
著名的羅伊普勒上尉 三角洲部隊的那個
Ah, Captain Roy Pulver, he of Delta Force fame.
你是誰
Who's this?
-克萊夫文托上校 -你是傑瑪的老闆
- This is Colonel Clive Ventor. - Jemma's boss.
-之前是 -她在嗎
- Until recently. - Is she around?
-不 很不幸她不在 -你知道她什麼時候回來嗎
- Well no, unfortunately she's not. - Do you know when she'll be back?
我不得不把這件事歸咎於不可抗力
Now that is more of a cosmic question that I'd have to hand over to a higher power.
-她死了 -什麼？
- She's dead. - What?
我不喜歡告訴別人壞消息
I hate to be the bearer of bad news, but
但威爾斯小姐昨晚摔斷了脖子
Miss Wells took a nasty spill and snapped her neck last night.
是在實驗室發生的意外
An accident in the lab,
加班時她可能已經很疲憊了
working late, likely very fatigued.
不…
No...
我可以問問你在哪兒嗎
Can I ask where you are?
-一 -二
- One. - Two.
這不是場意外
That was no fucking accident.
三
Three!
她為什麼會死？誰殺死的她？
Why is she dead? Who killed her?
我還沒能活得足夠久去查明真相
I've never lived long enough to find out.
好吧 我們在哪兒結束的來著？對了 那輛公車
Okay so, where were we? Oh yeah, the bus.
賤人
Fuck!
-看來他很堅持嘛  -親愛的 遇到牛仔啦
Oh honey, we've got ourselves a cowboy.
我得開始認真對待了
I think I'm gonna have to get serious here.
什麼鬼…
What the f...
我操
Fuck me!
臥…操！
Oh... Fuck!
活該倒楣
Nah, I think they deserved it.
-你好羅伊 -你好傑克
- Hey, Roy. - Hi, Jake.
你看起來像是剛從墳墓裡挖出來 怎麼搞的
You look like death taking a dump. What happened to you?
我只是醒錯了地方 我沒事
I just woke up wrong. I'm fine, Jake.
無所謂這都是常有的事了 你能給我一大瓶白酒嗎
It happens all the time. Can I get a large bottle of that Baijiu, please?
傑克，要不還是給我來兩大瓶
You know what, Jake? Make it two large bottles.
兩瓶 老天爺
Two! Jesus Christ!
我為你的肝默哀
Hear ye, hear ye! Sir Osis of Liver.
開玩笑的
I'm kidding.
酒鬼所見略同嘛
Alcoholics unanimous, am I right?
今朝有酒今朝醉，明日愁來明日愁
- You know you got today, right Jake? - Because tomorrow isn't guaranteed.
好詩啊好詩
Fuckin' A, pal. Fuckin' A.
這傢伙就快廢了
This kids is all about to shut down.
你怎麼能這樣喝酒啊
How can you drink like that?
-你怎麼不能呢 -不能
- How can you not? - You know,
很多國內的安全方面的專家 提醒你一下 我就是這樣的專家
a lot of expert internal security pundits, and mind you, I'm one of 'em
我告訴你 恐怖分子的下一個目標就是我們的釀酒廠了
think that next 9/11 will target our distilled spirits.
就在當下 全國的醉鬼加起來
Now, you have got a country where the rate of alcoholism
酗酒率高達38%
and binge drinking is somewhere in the 38th percentile
如果幹掉了這個國家的酒廠…
so should you wipe out...
這個傻逼叫戴夫
This douchebag's named Dave.
他是一家私人公司的安全專家
Dave is a security specialist at some private firm
無論我回答什麼 “你怎麼能這樣喝酒啊”
and it doesn't matter what my answer is to him asking "how can you drink like that?"
它總是用這麼愚蠢地話來開頭
he always launches into this exact same fucking speech.
我都可以逐字重複了
I know what he's gonna say word for word.
我一進來就知道會發生些什麼事
I know everything that's gonna happen from the second I walk in.
這個著名的中國擊劍運動員將在11:05到達
At 11:05, this famous Chinese swordfighter comes in.
她曾12次獲得世界冠軍
She was a twelve-time world champion.
我去！馮黛
Shit! Dai Feng.
-你知道這是最著名的… -中國劍術大師嗎
- You know she's one of the most famous... - Chinese sword masters?
-12次… -世界冠軍
- Twelve times... - World Champion.
-我跟你提到過她嗎 -快一百次了
- Have I told you about her? - A hundred times.
真的嗎我不記得了呀
Really? I don't remember.
-我記得 -佩德羅給馮師父準備桌子
- I do. - Pedro, prepare a table for Sifu Feng.
你好請坐
Hi. Please, sit.
馮師父就是我要擠進這家酒吧的原因
Sifu Feng, here, is the reason I have to bust my ass to get to the bar every day.
只要我在十一點之後到這 她都會坐在酒吧最後一個空位上
If I get here any later than eleven, she takes the last seat at the bar.
我去 她看我了
Shit. She just stared at me.
-你交過女朋友嗎 -你說什麼
- Have you ever been with a woman? - Excuse me?
你有沒有交過女朋友？
Have you ever been with a woman?
我這是姜太公釣魚 你懂的
I think I'm catching a fish, if you know what I mean.
我看你還不如頂著個小鳥在頭上 別人至少還能看你一眼 兄弟
I think you have a better chance of growing a penis on your forehead, Jake.
大約到中午
At around noon...
好吧 雖然我知道我這麼想是不對的
Okay. I feel a little bit bad about this next thing.
但我就是喜歡看到他滑倒 真抱歉
But I just love seeing him wipe out. I'm sorry.
我應該警告他的 但真他媽好笑
I know I should probably warn him, but it's just so fuckin' funny
我如今可很難有機會笑出來了
and it's not like I got a lot to laugh about these days.
你別在上班的時候給我搞事情 佩德羅 這可不算工傷
You can't file workman's comp. Pedro, no one will believe you.
12點20分 戴夫終於要回去工作了
At 12:20, Dave the pant loaf finally goes back to work.
你最好希望恐怖分子們不會開始對
You better hope the terrorists don't decide to
世界各地的白酒下毒了 羅伊
start poisoning the world's Baijiu supply, Roy.
那也等他們把那個小炸彈送走先
But not before delivering that little gut-buster.
-我給的太多了 -坐下戴夫
- That's too much. - Sit down, Dave.
-什麼 -我想跟你講個故事
- Excuse me? - I want to tell you a story.
我今天被炸了 說個小故事轉個場輕鬆一下
Okay, I'm bombed today. A little twist on the war story.
我開始談論有一次喝多了之後死了的情況
I start talking about the other times I've died when I've had too much to drink.
戴夫 你臉上中過槍嗎
Have you ever been shot in the face, Dave?
我中過
I was shot in the face.
我死前發生在我身上的趣事
A funny thing happened to be right before I died.
已經有一段時間了
This was a while back.
是一顆口徑0.45ACP的子彈
It was a .45 ACP round.
它飛過來 乾淨俐落
Enters here, clean.
穿透我的嘴再飛出來 幾乎完好無損
Bullet winds up in my mouth, almost intact
我記得我能感覺到烤牛排的味道
and I remember tasting steak.
是啊 就像一份美味的肋排
Yeah, like a really, really good rib-eye.
不一會兒 當我又活過來的時候
And it wasn't until much later, when I was alive again,
我說 “我去
I said, "Shit,
是我的舌頭被子彈的熱度烤熟了”
that was my tongue being cooked by the heat of the bullet."
我嘗到了自己的舌頭的味道
That's what I tasted. My tongue.
你能相信嗎 太他麼過癮了
Can you believe that shit? That's fuckin' wild.
這是個真實的故事 戴夫
That is a true story, Dave.
好故事啊夥計
Good stuff, buddy.
需要給你張沙發清醒清醒嗎
You ever thought about getting a sober coach?
懂了
Copy that.
就在12點47分不
At exactly 12:47... no,
要我說 在那一個瞬間
let me get to that in a second.
應該說是這十五分鐘，我是真的，真的很興奮
Let's say a quarter 'til, I've usually got a really, really good buzz,
我感覺真的很爽
and I'm feeling fuckin' good.
我一到酒吧
You see, as long as I make it to this bar,
直到他們找到我前我都可以暢飲
I can drink until they find me.
我可以和喝到完全崩潰
I can get absolutely shit-faced,
不省人事
and not feel a thing.
我從來沒有撐過12點47分這個點
12:47 PM. I've never, not once made it a minute past this point
為什麼我要放棄呢
Why do I let it happen.
為什麼不呢
Why not?
因為在這個酒吧外 無論我跑到哪裡 戰鬥到哪裡
Because outside this bar, no matter what direction I run
我從未活到過12點47分
and no matter how hard I fight, I have never lived past 12:47 PM.
他們總能幹掉我
They always get me.
一群我甚至都不知道為何要殺我的瘋子
A bunch of asshole I've never met, killing me for reasons
這對我來說是個謎
that remain a mystery.
而我的妹子 她死了
And she's dead. My girl.
她在離我很遠的地方死掉了
Gone in a moment further back than I can ever go.
我陷入了一個迴圈裡 永不停歇
Stuck here in the death loop of a never-ending day.
我知道我不應該讓自己醉成這樣
I know I can't keep drinking my way through it
不應該每次都以這種方式結束
not when every day ends like this.
我需要的是一個周全的計畫 我需要有人為此付出代價
I need a plan now. I need to make somebody pay.
但他們有一整支軍隊 而我只有時間
They have an army. All I have is time.
昨天就像是幾個月前的事
Yesterday was months ago.
很好
Great.
好很好
Yeah, that's good.
-請回避一下好嗎 -當然可以
- Guys, would you give me a second, please? - Sure.
我的天? 女人
My God, woman.
看看你
Look at you.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
你是對電話過敏了嗎
Have you developed some allergic reaction to phones?
不 我剛回來 我的手機還是關機狀態
No, I just got back. My cell phone is shut off and I didn't get a chance to
也還沒來得及弄座機電話 所以
square away my landline, so...
-所以他們也都關掉了 -是的
- So they shut that off too? - Yeah.
我是說 我真的很幸運
I mean, it's really just luck
-你能和我聯繫上  -是的
- that you got in touch with me at all. - Yeah.
在你公寓樓底部的酒吧裡找到你
The amount of luck it took to find you
真的需要很多運氣
in the bar at the bottom of your apartment building
有多大的可能性呢
What were the odds?
諷刺得真好 你過得怎麼樣 陌生人
Well hello there sarcasm. How you been, stranger?
我很久沒聽到你的消息了
Haven't heard from you in a while.
-這是什麼 -我帶了一份簡歷
- What's that? - I brought a resume.
印表機墨不夠了 三角洲部隊那部分看不太清
The printer I used was low on ink so the Delta Force section is hard to read.
這會降低我的機會嗎
That gonna hurt my chances?
過來
Come here.
這裡要穿制服
They wear uniforms here. So just...
是啊這很好啊
Alright cool, yeah.
-我需要 -他們不是 哇喔
- I need to just... - I mean, it's not those...
但願他們不是商場裡 那種穿褐紅色衣服的保安 我可受不了
Those maroon things, like mall security because I can't rock them.
褐紅色 像我的裙子這樣？
Maroon, like... my dress?
不像你的裙子 因為那樣就太性感了
No, not like your dress, because that would be sexy.
-我就那麼一說 -行吧
- No, I'm just saying. - Fine.
不過 這裡的待遇怎麼樣
Anyway, I... What is the salary here?
具體情況你清楚嗎 這裡有那種健康補助嗎？
Do you have any idea? Is there a medical co-pay
因為我以前在特種部隊裡的時候有
because I have pre-existing-- You know with the combat stuff.
話說回來 你們在這裡做什麼 這兒可真大
Anyway, what are you doing here? It looks really big.
-你已經做了很長時間了嗎 -我希望是夠長了
- Been working on it a while? - Just long enough, I hope.
到底是多少
What is that thing, anyway.
五年不眠不休的持續研究
That's five years of sleepless nights and round-the-clock research.
這對我來說比你想像的更重要
And it means more to me than you can possibly imagine.
-它是做什麼的 -它是做什麼的
- What does it do? - What does it do?
如果使用不當
It unmakes all of time and space.
它將摧毀時間和空間 毀滅整個地球
And destroys the planet in its entirety if improperly used.
真的假的？ 就像電影“審判日”那種情形嗎
No shit? Like "doomsday" destroy?
你一定壓力很大
You must be really stressed.
哇喔 看看喬
Wow, look at Joe.
天? 他長大了 傑瑪
Jesus, he's getting so big, Jemma.
你介意我取出來嗎
Hey, you mind if I swap this out?
這張照片照片你還有嗎
This picture, you got another one of these?
當然拿走這張吧 你有多重
Oh yeah sure, you can take it. What's your weight?
我很健康大約80公斤吧
I'm doing a special paleo thing so it's like 175
你還喝酒嗎
Still drinking?
-喝呀 -我寫82公斤吧
- Yeah. - I'll put 180.
你有想過要告訴他嗎
Have you thought about telling him?
這對我來說很重要 傑瑪
It would mean a lot to me if we could tell him, Jemma.
那對他有什麼好處呢 你已經離開了他大半輩子了
Honestly, what would he gain? You've been absent for most of his life.
你為什麼把我現在去瞭解他
Why do you have to say it like that?
說得好像不值一提似的
Like it wouldn't be worth it if I got to know him now.
-是工作把我從你身邊帶走了
My work took me away from you guys.
-你的工作嗎 -是的
- Your work? - Yeah
你的工作嗎
Your work?
你更喜歡那種生活 而不是與我們一起分享
You loved that life a lot more than you loved the idea of sharing one with us.
射擊比尿布和顧家更讓你興奮
Getting shot at is way more exciting than diapers and minivans.
很明顯 對我你永遠都有理?
Right right right, there's your go-to argument and you know that.
我就是那個沒留下來的混蛋是嗎
I'm just the asshole who didn't want to stick around, right?
還有什麼關係呢
What does it matter any more, Roy?
我們倆做的決定 我們向前看 喬還是很崇拜你的
We both moved on, we've made our decision, and Joe adores you anyway.
-他崇拜我嗎 -對
- He adores me? - Yeah.
他怎麼說我的
What'd he say about me?
你想要什麼羅伊
What do you want, Roy?
我失去了你
I lost you, okay?
我知道我搞砸了我接受
I know that I blew it. I made my peace with it.
我不想這種事發生在我兒子身上
Please don't let that happen with my son.
我不敢渴望更多了
That's all I'm asking.
他是我們的孩子 傑瑪
He's our boy, Jemma.
-威爾斯博士 -等一會兒
- Doctor Wells. - Just a minute.
抱歉 佈雷特
Oh, sorry Brett.
這位是 羅伊 羅伊 這位是佈雷特
This is Roy. Roy, Brett.
他是這裡的安保主管
Brett's head of security here at Dynow.
你的辦公室是限制區域 威爾斯博士
Your office is in a restricted area, Dr. Wells
-因此不能隨意進出 -我清楚地向上校解釋了
- and is therefore off limits. - I made it clear to the Colonel
我會在我認為合適的時候接待來訪者
that I would accept visitors when I deemed it appropriate.
我只是帶簡歷來 大個子 別激動
I was just dropping off my resume, big guy. It's all good.
我們目前不對外招聘
We're not hiring right now.
-普勒上尉 -告訴他我馬上就到
- Captain Pulver. - Tell him I'll be there in a moment.
上校在等
The Colonel's waiting.
真是個混蛋
What a dick.
-你不是說你們在招人嗎 -他們是在招人 我們正在招人
- I thought you said you were hiring. - They are. We are.
是我在招人
I am.
你在說什麼
What are you talking about?
是一個專項細緻的特種安保工作
It's a very specific security detail.
是什麼秘密的東西比如黑匣子之類的嗎
Black bag stuff? Like covert?
-不止 -真的嗎
- Beyond. - Really?
我什麼時候開始
When do I start?
比你想的要早
Sooner than you think.
我讀過那個人的生平 我覺得有必要擔心一下
I read the man's resume and I see cause for concern.
看起來沒什麼大不了的
He doesn't look like much.
沒人會注意到蒼蠅 除非他把一碗好湯弄爛了
No one ever notices the housefly until he fucks up a good bowl of soup.
我不喜歡他
There's something I don't like about him.
他有那種 特性
He has that... trait.
什麼特性
What trait is that?
雖天資尚佳，卻懂勤能補拙
The overachiever who makes up for a lack of talent with hustle.
我一直都討厭這樣的人
The guy on the playground I grew up hating.
查一下他的服役記錄 如果他留下了 我想時刻關注著他
Vet his service history. If it's accurate, I want him tracked and monitored.
如果他惹麻煩 我們會處理的
If he becomes problematic, we'll deal with him.
找一些週邊的人員
And reach outside the normal ranks,
這樣就沒人能把他的事和我們聯繫起來了 越隨機越好
no one that could connect back to us. The more random the assets, the better.
找些怪胎來做這個事
Find some real freaks.
行了我要離開這裡去喝點酒 也許…
Okay, I'm gonna get out of here, grab a little vino, maybe some--
-等等 我要修修你的頭髮 -哦 傑瑪
- Just let me fix your hair. - Ow, Jemma!
我在流血
I'm bleeding.
-你收到我送的生日禮物了嗎
Did you get my birthday present, Roy?
-你在這裡是做什麼的 你表現得很奇怪
What are you doing here? You're acting so weird.
你收到了嗎 我寄給你的
Did you get it? The present. I sent it to you.
-我不知道 我沒看 -看看吧 我幾天前寄給你的
- I don't know. I haven't checked. - Well please do. I sent it a few days ago.
好吧 當然我會看一看
I will. Of course I will.
威爾斯博士 我能見一下你嗎
Dr. Wells, could I see you for a moment.
-我得去醫院了 -我馬上 上校
- I'll have to go to the hospital. - I'll be there in a moment, Colonel.
-你取了我的血 -現在仔細聽我說 羅伊
- You drew blood. - Listen to me now, Roy.
我知道我們最近沒見過多少面
Okay look, I know we haven't seen much of each other lately
我知道我們已經分道揚鑣
and I know we've gone down very different paths.
-我知道 但當我 -聽著 這很重要
- I know, but when I... - It's important that you listen. Just listen!
-好 好 說吧 -行
- You talk. You talk. - Okay.
我忘記了 這有多難
I forgot how trying this can be.
我在喬身上看到了很多你的影子 真的
I see a lot of you in Joe, I do.
他有決心 還有無論如何都要成功的意志
His determination, his willingness to succeed no matter what.
他有著你最好的品質 但也有你的自私
He has some of your best qualities, but he also has your selfishness
你玩消失的能力和你一樣的厲害
and your ability to just disappear when it suits him.
-我以為一切都已經結束了 -逃避責任
- Just when I thought we were turning a corner. - And run from responsibility.
好吧很好你想從我這裡得到什麼告訴我吧
Okay, alright. What do you want from me? Just tell me. Just tell me!
我想要那個我很久以前就愛上了的男人
I want the man I fell in love with a long time ago,
帶給我一個兒子的男人
the one who gave me a son
強大自信的你
the strong, confident version of you,
不是那個每晚都在外面 和不同的婊子亂搞的羅伊
not the Roy who's out every night getting hammered and banging a different bimbo.
-記住這個 歐西裡斯 歐西裡斯 -好的
- Remember this: Osiris. Osiris. - Okay.
看啊 好一對吃飯不花錢兄弟
Look, it's Roid and Rage.
吃那麼多小心三高啊 朋友
You know carbohydrates are not your friend, fellas.
-威爾斯博士 你還好嗎 -是的
- Doctor Wells, are you well? - Yes.
-你介意我吸煙嗎 -不 一點也不
- Does cigar smoke botther you? - No, not at all.
主軸怎麼樣了
The Spindle.
那個 進度目前有點耽擱
Well, we're experiencing a minor delay at the moment.
明確一下時間
Define minor.
一周最多兩周
A week, two weeks at the most.
-為什麼 -研發不是一門精確的科學
- And why? - R&D is never an exact science.
但這正是我們想要的精確科學
But that's exactly what we're after; exact science.
你的朋友 普勒上尉
Your friend, Captain Pulver.
-是的 他來了一份簡歷 -你對他提起過這裡嗎
- Yes, he dropped off a resume. - And whatever possessed him.
那個也許我以前跟他提到過實驗室裡的軍事力量
Well, I may have mentioned in passing the military presence here at the lab.
你有提起過嗎
And whatever possessed you?
此設施的安全協定不應成為私密對話的主題
The security protocols of this facility should not be the subject of pillow talk.
我可以向你保證 你擔心的事情不會發生
I can assure you, they're not.
-羅伊和我不是 -你是他孩子的母親
- Roy and I are not... - You are the mother of his child, no?
請坐 隨意一些
Please sit down. Make yourself comfortable.
我不想讓這看起來像是審問
I don't want this to seem like an interrogation.
我不想長篇大論
I'm not one for long stories,
我是個喜歡簡潔的人
I'm someone who's always appreciated brevity in any form.
無論何種形式 越短越好 然而
The shorter the better. However,
我自己也有一個故事 我不斷重複的敘述過
I do have one story that I've told and retold
現在要分享給你
and it's a story that I'd like to share with you now,
如果你願意的話
if you'll indulge me.
-我喜歡長故事 -那正好
- I happen to like long stories. - Oh good, then we're both in luck.
1979年我在緬甸為中情局工作
So, Burma 1979, I was doing skunk work for the CIA,
我們足足花了十年的時間
smuggling enough opium into the country to backstop
利用走私大量的鴉片到這個國家 來支持並發動了一場血腥的軍事政變
a very bloody military coup that we would eventually stage a decade later.
所有這些通常都是最高機密
This is all mostly declassified, mostly.
不管怎樣
At any rate, I find myself
我在仰光郊外的叢林裡
in the jungle outside Rangoon,
在一場持續三天的交火中狙擊克倫民族聯盟解放陣線的士兵
sniping soldiers from the KNU Liberation Front in a three-day running firefight
這讓我損失了整個團隊
that cost me my entire team.
最後，我面臨的
So there I am,
是一群骯髒的 瘋狂的
on the verge of being overrun by a bunch of machete-wielding rebels
揮舞著彎刀的叛亂分子
who have terrible attitudes and even worse hygiene
而我只能在36個小時不眠不休的情況下
and all I have is a Remington Buckmaster with a shot-out scope
用一杆帶狙擊鏡的刺刀步槍去苛求勝利
and 36 sleepless hours in which to squeeze out a win.
然後我聽到了
And then I hear it.
刺耳的尖叫聲
This piercing squeal,
就像水壺燒開 水蒸汽的哨聲
like a steam whistle.
一頭能讓你嚇得尿褲子的
Wild boar.
大野豬
Make you piss your pants.
光是聲音就足以讓叛軍四散
The sound alone is enough to make the rebels scatter.
沒人敢去觸碰那些鋒利的獠牙
No one wants to fuck with the tusks.
而那頭那個狗娘養的畜生聞到了我的味道 直奔我而來
So now this son-of-a-bitch gets a sniff of me and comes at me straight away.
我寧肯對付十個兇惡的敵人 也不願面對這一隻野獸
Now I'd rather put a bullet in ten men than kill an animal,
但我還沒來得及現身
but before I'm even presented
一條近6米長的緬甸蟒蛇從榕樹上竄下來
with the do-or-die of it all, an 18 foot Burmese Python
把這頭狂暴的野豬像聖誕火腿一樣纏繞起來
comes down from a banyan tree and wraps up this raging hog like a Christmas ham.
我從沒見過這樣的情形
I've never seen anything like it.
接下來的幾個小時 我就驚奇地看著
And for the next few hours, I watch in wonder as this
黑蟒如何吞咽 豬如何被消化
snake slowly suffocates and devours this pig.
周圍一片寂靜 我什麼都能聽見
It was oddly quiet so I could hear everything.
野豬的骨頭啪啪作響 當它的肺崩潰時
The boar's bones snapping, the bellow's-like wheeze as its lungs collapsed
風箱般的喘息聲使它聽起來像蛇在笑
that made it sound like the snake was laughing.
這仍然是我所見過的最令人驚詫的暴力行為
It remains the most awe-inspiring act of violence I have ever seen.
但我印象最深刻的
But what struck me most
是即使巨蟒張開了它的嘴 要吃掉它的獵物
even as the python extended its jaws a full two feet to devour its prey,
她的眼睛裡仍透著鎮靜和冷酷的算計
was the calm and calculation in its eyes.
直到後來當它移動身體中部
And wasn't until later, when it finally moved its mid-section
透過野豬的拱形輪廓
now distended with the outline of that boar
我看到了一窩蛋
that I saw a dozen eggs.
蟒蛇蛋
Python eggs.
野豬幾乎踩爛了它的巢
The boar was about to trample its nest.
所以我最初認為這是一種侵略行為
So what I had first perceived as an act of aggression,
事實上這是一種愛的行為
was actually an act of love.
蟒蛇殺死野豬不是出於怨恨
The snake killing the boar not out of malice,
而是為了保護它們的後代
but out of necessity to prevent its future from being obliterated.
我很喜歡這個故事
I enjoyed that story.
我很高興能講給你我也覺得很合適
Oh and I enjoyed telling it. I also thought it apt.
-為什麼呢 -實驗室裡不會再有訪客
- How so? - No more visitors to the lab.
沒有前男友 舊情人或什麼過去的影子
No ex-boyfriends, old flames or shadowy figures from the past,
如果工作要延期
if there's a delay in the work
-我想要立刻得到通知
I want to be apprised of it post-haste.
好嗎 -當然
- Yes? - Of course.
謝謝你 博士 很好
Thank you, doctor. That's wonderful.
小心腳下
Do watch your step.
-你要再來點嗎 -還有什麼
- You want another one? - Another one what?
你真可愛
You are sweet.
你們倆認識多久了
How long have you two known each other?
我們今天才認識
We only met today.
-他是我最好的新朋友 -是啊 我是
- He is my newest best friend. - Yes I am.
-愛麗絲是個牙科保健師 -說起來奇怪 我其實無比討厭牙齒
- Alice is a dental hygienist. - Which is weird 'cuz I totally hate teeth.
它們的構造就讓我噁心
I mean, just the texture of them grosses me out.
-牙醫職業看起來 -就像我最不該做的事嗎
- Then a career in dentistry seems like... - Like the last thing I should be doing?
是啊 我知道 我知道 但我願意接受每一個挑戰
Yeah, I know, I know. But I'm all about the challenge.
我喜歡走出舒適區
I like to push myself out of the comfort zone.
-這是真正成長的唯一途徑 -宇宙真理
- It's the only way to grow, really. - So true.
他很可愛不是嗎
He's so pretty. Isn't he pretty?
你們倆認識多久了
How long have you guys known each other?
跟加布裡埃爾嗎 太久了 就像我在酒吧裡喝的東西一樣久
With Gabrielle? For as long as I've been drinking in this bar.
-自從他從海外回來 -危險的經歷 告訴我嘛
- Since you got back from overseas. - Oh, danger. Do tell!
女士們 真沒什麼好說的
Ladies, there's really almost nothing to tell.
-所以什麼都不告訴我們咯 -不過你能等一下嗎 因為
- Then tell us almost nothing. - Can you wait? Because...
我要去撒尿 馬上回來
I've gotta pee. I'll be right back.
你該帶她回家 羅伊
You should take her home, Roy.
你該帶她回家
You should take her home.
你得問
You have to ask:
我為什麼不能把你跟她都帶回家呢 加布裡埃爾
"Why not take you home too, Gabrielle?"
我會說
And I will say...
也許下次吧
Maybe another night.
你開始說胡話了
I'm starting to wear you down.
但那個夜晚永遠不會到來
我們可以玩得很開心 羅伊 但我們永遠不會相愛
We'd have fun, Roy, but we'd never be in love.
-但是 愛
Oh, love.
-不 -為什麼
- No. - Why?
-為什麼 -是啊
- Why? - Yeah.
因為你仍然還愛著其他人
Because you're still in love... with someone else.
我能從你的眼睛裡看出來
It's in your eyes.
在那抹哀傷之中
In the sadness I see there.
你渴望著一個女人 但不是我
There is a woman you long for, but it's not me.
也不是我們親愛的牙科保健員
And it's not our lovely hygienist.
酒吧 你好 是
Bar, hello? Yeah.
-找你的 -誰會現在給我打電話
- It's for you. - Who wants to call me now.
-我不知道 -你好
- I don't know. - Hello?
羅伊你能聽到我嗎 -傑瑪 怎麼
- Roy, can you hear me? - Jemma? What...
你還在實驗室嗎 現在都接近淩晨3點了
Are you still at the lab? It's almost 3AM.
傑瑪 你還好嗎
Jemma, are you okay?
-你還好嗎 -是的 我沒事 但是
- You alright? - Yeah, I'm fine, but...
-怎麼回事 聽著 -你聽我說
- What's going on? Listen... - Yeah, listen to me.
我也許做了瘋狂的事
I think I might have to do something drastic
如果發生什麼事答應我你去做你該做的
and if anything happens, promise me you'll do what you do--
-我聽不到你講話了 -我需要你的?明
- I can't-- I can't hear you. - I'm gonna need your help.
怎麼回事你還好嗎
Wait, what's going on? Are you okay?
我不能解釋給你聽 你還不明白
I can't explain it right now, but you wouldn't understand anyway.
我想是斷線了
Hey, I think I lost you.
傑瑪 給我回電話 好嗎
Jemma, call me back, okay?
-是誰 -我前任
- Who was that? - It was my ex...
她看起來有些工作過度了
and she was... she sounded pretty worked up.
看起來我們親愛的博士是個壞人
It seems our dear doctor has gone rogue.
找到她
Find her.
我錯過了什麼
What did I miss?
你好
Oh, hi.
我們剛剛討論了這個星球上最性感的人 你的名字出現了
We were talking about the hottest people on the planet and naturally your name came up.
我應該打電話給傑瑪的
I should have tried to call Jemma back when
但我喝醉了 性欲旺盛 我並不在乎
I was drunk and horny and I didn't give a shit.
我不知道那有多重要
I didn't know how important it was.
我不知道 這會是我最後一次聽到她的聲音
I didn't know it would be the last time that I'd ever hear her voice.
有些事是無法挽回的
Some things you can't re-do.
你就不得不一次又一次地做一些事情
And some things you're forced to do over and over again.
我知道這一切都跟她密不可分
I know this whole thing leads back to her.
我只是不知道這是怎麼回事
I just have no idea what "this whole thing" actually is.
你收到我的生日禮物了嗎
Did you get my birthday present?
你收到禮物了嗎
Did you get it, the present?
-我不知道我沒看 -看看吧 我幾天前寄給你的
- I don't know, I haven't checked. - Well please do, I sent it a few days ago.
記住這個 歐西裡斯
Remember this: Osiris.
生日快樂 羅伊 永遠向前看 記住
"Happy birthday, Roy. May you always live your life forward and remember:"
時間不等人
"Time waits for no man."
好吧該死
Fuck me.
再來一遍
Let's do that again.
有人要搶我的車！
I'm being car-jacked!
臥槽
Fuck!
快點快點我們走
Come on, come on, let's go.
-老兄 見鬼 終於 -擋住我的路了
- Dude, die already, god damn it! - He's in my way.
他媽的時間到了
About fuckin' time.
有人要搶我的啊！
I'm being car-jacked!
開車的時候別看東西 你個白癡
Don't read and drive, moron.
我怎麼會沒注意到呢
How did I never notice this?
該死 我錯過了去中餐館的路口
Shit, I missed the exit to the chinese restaurant.
上次我去別的地方 結果真是糟透了
The last time I went anywhere else, it ended up really bad.
很明顯 我把這位叫做笑臉
I call this guy Smiley, for obvious reasons.
被射中就像一記耳光一樣簡單明瞭
At least getting shot is simple. Straight-forward stuff.
對 我抓到他了
誰會想到他這麼垃圾啊
Who the hell thinks up shit like this?
我抓到他了
我一直在逃避我的生活
All I've been doing is running from my life this entire time.
現在我第一次清楚明瞭的有了方向
Now I've got my first real clue to what the fuck might be happening to me.
現在我需要的是找一個
All I need now is a little cease-fire
安靜的地方來讀書
and somewhere quiet where I can get some reading done.
歐西裡斯和伊西斯是對忠城的夫妻
Osiris and Isis were a devoted husband and wife.
她是埃及高級女祭司 理想中的母親和妻子
She was an Egyptian high priestess, an ideal mother and wife,
死亡的守護者
protector of the dead,
精通來世之旅的所有咒語
skilled in all magical spells for transport through the afterlife and beyond.
歐西裡斯最終被他的敵人肢解
Osiris was eventually dismembered
被切成14塊 分散在埃及各地
into fourteen parts and scattered across Egypt by his enemy.
這算什麼禮物
What the fuck kind of birthday present is this?
生日快樂 羅伊 永遠向前看 記住
Happy birthday, Roy. May you always live your life forward and remember:
時間不等人
Time waits for no man.
喬？ 他到底在做什麼
Joe. What the hell's he doing?
糟糕
Shit.
他並不知道他媽媽死了 現在他孤單一個人
He doesn't know his mom is gone, and he's all alone now.
我現在是他唯一的家人了
That I'm the only family he has left.
-你好嗎 夥計 -門票是10美元
- How you doing? - Ten dollar entry, broham.
每輪5次雙淘汰制
Five dollar per round, double elimination.
你們在這裡做什麼
What uh... What you got going here?
-體育比賽 -這是什麼
- Pop-up e-sport tourney. - What is that?
電子遊戲比賽
Competitive video gaming.
我們主要經營80年代的復古遊戲
Yeah, we do mostly eighties-based retro side-scrollers
雙龍 變身野獸 街頭霸王
Double Dragon, Altered Beast, Street Fighter.
我們是純粹主義者 兄弟 致力於電子遊戲的黃金時代
We're purists, bro. Dedicated to video games' golden age.
模擬或死亡 8位遊戲是狗屎
Analog or death. 8-bit is the shit.
-你多大了 -41 時光飛逝
- How old are you? - The big four one. Life creeps up.
-41歲嗎 -是
- Forty-one? - Yeah.
-你有兒子了嗎 -我是故意裝幼稚的 兄弟
- You got a son here or something? - I'm childless by choice, bro.
好選擇
Whose choice?
不用找了
Keep it.
喬 嗨
Joe yo, hey.
嘿 夥計 -羅伊 嗨 你好嗎
- Hi bud. - Roy. Hey, what's up?
讓我們看看你 你嚇到我了
Look at you, you've shot way up, huh?
上次我見到你的時候 你才這麼高
I think you were like yay high last time I saw you.
-我不知道 你人間蒸發了 -我沒有人間蒸發
- I didn't know you were a gamer. - Oh, I am not a gamer.
-你在這裡做什麼
So what are you doing here?
-我也想問你同樣的問題 你不需要去學校嗎
Actually, I was going to ask you the same question, buddy. Isn't it a school day?
我翹課了
I ditched.
得了 夥計 你不需要這樣
Come on, buddy, you can do better than this.
那個我不能不來
Well, I couldn't not come.
這些是我最喜歡的遊戲
These are like my favourite vintage video games.
媽媽會因為我在這裡而生氣的
And mom would be really mad if she knew I was here.
媽媽會生氣的
Mom would be really mad.
如果你告訴我一件事 我就不會跟她說
I tell you what, I won't rat you out if you tell me one thing.
-好啊
Okay...
-你從樓上的那個人那裡買了什麼很老的那個人
What did you buy from that boy upstairs? The older boy?
-我什麼都沒買 -喬 我看到你了
- I didn't buy anything. - Joe, I saw you.
這是一張角色扮演類遊戲卡 我跟他換的
It's an RPG card game. I traded it with that kid.
你可以成為殺手 傭兵什麼的
You can be like all these different assassins and mercenaries and stuff...
-真的很好玩 -我猜也是
- It's really cool. - I bet it is.
你從他那裡得到的嗎
So this is what you got from him?
你以為我在買毒品什麼的嗎
Did you think I was buying drugs or something?
-或者類似的東西
Or something.
-我才11歲 我不可以這樣做
I just turned eleven, I can't do that stuff.
-你永遠都不能那樣做好嗎
You can't do that stuff ever, pal. Okay?
-是嗎 -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
好了 來吧 言歸正傳 我想跟你聊一聊 好嗎
Let's go get some lunch, we can come back okay? I want to talk to you.
-螢幕還壞了 -太垃圾了 走吧
- The screen is broken anyway. - Ah, piece of junk. Come on.
你餓嗎 -餓
- You hungry, buddy? - Yeah.
-是嗎 那你最喜歡吃什麼 -披薩
- Yeah? What's your favourite food? - Pizza.
披薩嗎 那我們就吃披薩 壽司怎麼樣
Pizza? We can go get some pizza. What about sushi?
-我不喜歡壽司 -不喜歡嗎
- I don't like sushi. - You don't?
-不 -為什麼
- No. - How come?
-就因為那是壽司 -是哈 有道理
- Because it's sushi. - Oh, that makes sense.
我現在應該告訴他
I have to tell him now.
告訴他媽媽死了 他永遠也見不到她了
Tell him his mother is gone. That him that he was never gonna see her again.
-告訴他 -你知道嗎 媽媽說你很混蛋耶
- Tell him that... - You know, Mom says you're a badass.
混蛋
Badass?
-她是這麼說的嗎 -她倒沒用這個詞
- She says that? - Well, she doesn't use that word,
但她說你就像個海軍陸戰隊員或者士兵
but she says you're like a SEAL team guy or something, like a soldier.
-媽媽提到過我嗎 -是啊說過好多
- Mom talks about me? - Yeah, she mentions you a lot.
很多嗎
A lot?
嘿 你就像颶風營救裡的那個人 有什麼特殊能力來著
Are you like that guy, the one from Taken, who has a particular set of skills
-連姆尼森嗎 -對
- Liam Neeson? - Yeah.
好吧 他就像是假的硬漢 我可是真漢子
Well, he's like a fake tough guy. I'm really guy.
-真的嗎 -我不騙你
- Really? - I'm not kidding you, that's real.
這很好啊
Oh, that's so cool.
嘿 喬
Hey, Joe.
我得跟你說點事夥計
I gotta tell you something, bud.
但這並不會發生 聽著 好嗎
And it's gonna be pretty hard to hear, okay?
但是 又很難把它用簡單的方式表達出來
I don't have an easy way to say this.
12點50分
Twelve fifty.
比我活時間長了三分鐘
Three minutes longer than I've ever lived.
怎麼回事
How?
裡面是全金屬的
The inside is all metal.
然後我進到了地下
Then I went below ground.
他們在監視著我
They're tracking me.
你想告訴我什麼啊羅伊
What did you want to tell me, Roy?
喬
Joe...
我是你的父親
I'm your father.
帶著滿滿的恐懼
In all that fear
我一瞬間看到了兒子對我的愛
I saw my son's love for me for a split second.
這太美好了
And it was beautiful.
請讓這次的死亡成為最後一次吧
Please. Please, let this death be the last.
狗娘養的
Motherfucker!
-你們是怎麼監視我的 -操你媽
- How are you tracking me? - Fuck you!
敢玩我 設備在哪裡
Fuck me? Where's the device?
-在你的屁眼裡 -你想得太多了
- Up your ass. - Oh, you're full of ideas!
-操你媽 -好吧 就這樣吧
- Fuck off. - Okay, fuck off!
嗨夥計
Hey, buddy!
好吧如果你想用你就用吧
Okay. When you gotta go, you gotta go.
追蹤器在哪兒呢
Where's this tracker?
它一定在這裡的某個地方 但在哪裡呢
I know it's here...
該死
Fuck.
佩德羅你不能幫我看一下嗎
Pedro, you want to help me look?
然後我說 我看到你的反情報專家了
And then I said, "I will see your counter-intelligence expert
我會教你一個專門的預防監控方法 朋友
and raise you a counter-surveillance specialist, my friend."
-你應該看看他們的表情 -你真是個白癡
- You should have seen the look on his face. - You... you're crazy!
-戴夫 -嗨 羅伊 -嗨
- Dave. - Hey, Roy.
-抱歉打斷你 -我剛告訴傑克那些混蛋
- Sorry to interrupt. - I was just telling Jake about this loudmouth...
我明白太好了 戴夫 你懂一些監控設備
Got it, great. Dave, you know something about tracking devices.
我對這些東西一無所知 羅伊
I don't know anything about that kind of thing, Roy.
我的確對這些東西瞭若指掌
I know everything about that kind of thing.
-什麼樣的設備
What are we talking?
-傳統的應答器嗎 -用來追蹤人的東西
- Traditional transponder? - The kind you put on a person.
-是附在身體上的還是植入體內的 -哪種更好
- A body-based or an implantable device. - What's better?
當你不想讓被監視人意識到自己在被監視的話
If you don't want the person to know they're being tracked.
那麼植入物就更合適了
Well, an implantable version is loads more reliable.
-另一種是附著在衣服上
A body-based device would be attached to clothing--
-一般植入到哪裡 你會把它放哪兒呢
Where would you implant it? Where would you do it?
-大多數人認為只是
Well, most people think subcutaneously,
-在皮膚下 -那你會把它放哪兒
- just underneath the skin - Where would you it?
你是說我 個人習慣嗎 -你 你的個人習慣
- Oh, you mean me, personally? - You, personally.
戴夫的專長啊
A Dave special.
-那個愚蠢的詞是什麼意思 -對 對
What does that stupid face mean? Yeah. Yeah.
他明白了 是牙齒 羅伊 你的牙齒
He gets it. Your teeth, Roy. Your teeth!
最好是臼齒
Ideally a molar.
我勒個去的
You gotta be shitting me.
你戴著面罩很帥氣
You look so handsome with the mask on.
你什麼都不用害怕 深呼吸
You have nothing to worry about. Just keep breathing deeply.
很快就結束了
It'll all be over soon.
另外 你的嘴是一個天然的載體
Also, your mouth acts as a natural transmitter.
-戴夫 -怎麼
- Dave? - Yes?
你能幫我看看我的牙齒
Would you be able to look at a tooth
找找我有沒有這個裝置嗎
and detect if there was a tracking device in it?
如果在別人嘴裡就不行
I mean, not while it's inside someone mouth
-我可以查出牙齒是否被拔掉過 -傑克
- If that tooth were removed I could check it out. - Jake.
給我一瓶白酒和兩把鉗子
A large bottle of Baijiu and a pair of pliers, now.
不 不 不 天殺的傷口
No no no! God damn!
別擔心 戴夫 會再長好的
Don't worry, Dave, it'll grow back.
你瘋了嗎 不你需要幫助
Have you lost your mind? No, you need some damn help!
你就能幫到我 所以 你覺得怎麼樣
Not while your being so helpful. What do you think?
-不會 -是嗎
- No. - You sure?
-當然 -現在幾點了
- I'm positive. - What time is it?
-該死12點45分了 -見鬼 還剩2分鐘
- Shit. It's 12:45. - Oh shit. Only two minutes.
不要再從嘴裡拔牙了
It's time for you to stop snatching your damn teeth out of your mouth.
你瘋了嗎
Are you crazy?
見鬼 不 不 不 天?
- Fuck this shit. - No no no! God!
我本該在家裡坐著的
I should have stayed my black ass at home.
看快看
- Look. Look! - No!
-天吶 -有什麼嗎
- Oh my God. - What?
-有 這顆牙
Yeah. That tooth.
-這顆牙有點不規則
There's an irregularity in that tooth.
-真的嗎 -是的
- There is? - Yeah.
天? 我得看看裡面
Oh my God. I would need to see inside of it.
羅伊 -是
- Roy? - Yeah.
-小心好嗎 -好
- Carefully. - Yeah...
小心不這可不能小心
Carefully. No, that's not careful!
-狗娘養的 -我的天
- Son of a bitch. - Oh my God.
羅伊 有人為了監視你花了一大筆錢
Roy? Someone paid a lot of money to keep track of you.
-真的嗎 -是的 真的 我從來沒
- They did? - Yeah. A whole lot. I've never...
回頭見戴夫
I'll see you soon, Dave.
-是誰讓你把追蹤裝置放到我嘴裡的 -一個叫佈雷特的傢伙
- Who put the tracking device in my mouth? - A guy named Brett.
娘炮先生 肥肉男
Mr. Frat Boy, fake-bake bald
染過鬍子的400斤的高個安保主管
four hundred pound "I dye my beardhair black" douchebag head of Dynow security.
佈雷特
Brett.
我要在他胸口打個大洞
I'm gonna punch a giant fucking hole in his chest.
-你好嗎 -傑克
-what's up bro. -jack.
我需要一大瓶白酒和兩把鉗子
I need a large bottle of Baijiu and a pair of pliers, now.
我到今天為止已經死掉144次了
I have died one hundred and forty four times as of today,
但在這個特殊的日子裡 我終於能做點什麼了
but this particular day, I finally get to do something about it.
放下
Drop it.
-什麼這顆牙嗎 -不 不是這顆牙
- What, the tooth? - No, not the tooth.
不 我不會放下槍的
I'm not dropping it.
要不你放下槍 要不我就讓你中槍
Well it drops or you drop.
這是一把手工打造的沃爾特PPK
This is a custom handmade Walther PPK
在拍賣會上花了我將近50萬
that cost me nearly half a million dollars at auction.
你花了半百萬買了個炮仗嗎
You bought a handgun for half a million dollars?
還從一個私人槍手那裡 買到了經典SD-22消音器
And had my personal pistolsmith fit it with a vintage SD-22 SpielWaffen suppressor
世界上僅有6個每個25萬美元
of which there are six in the world, for an additional $250,000.
-這就75萬了 -完全正確
- 750,000 bucks. - Correct.
為什麼帕姆你為什麼要做這樣的事
Why in the fuck, Pam, would you ever do something like that?
-帕姆是誰
Pam?
-我不知道你的名字 所以就叫你帕姆了
Well, I never got your name so I just call you Pam.
-我們以前見過嗎 -許多次 過去見過許多次
- We've met? - Many, many times. In passing.
我想看看 慢慢地給我
Let me see it. Slow.
用關節挑著它
Hold her by the trigger guard.
請像對待瓷器一樣對待它
Handle it as if it were porcelain, please.
像蜘蛛網一樣溫柔
Soft as a whisper.
啊 -阿道夫希特勒
- AH? - Adolf Hitler.
-什麼 -卡爾沃爾特的私人禮物
- Que? - It was a personal gift from Carl Walther.
希特勒把它放在了慕尼克的辦公桌上
Hitler kept it in his desk in Munich.
殺死我的一直是希特勒的槍嗎
You've been killing me with fuckin' Hitler's gun this whole time?
-1945年被一名美國士兵偷走了 -上帝啊
- It was stolen by an American serviceman in 1945. - Jesus Christ.
-你有什麼毛病 -保存至今
- What is wrong with you? - Fast forward to the present day.
-每一分錢都在它身後 -我本以為不會更糟了 但事實如此
- It cost me a very pretty penny. - I didn't think this could get any worse.
-誰派你來的 -你不會想知道的
- Who sent you? - Wouldn't you like to know.
-我堅持要知道 -不要
- Hint hint. - Never.
-你現在打算要殺掉我嗎 -不 帕姆 我會朝你開槍
- Are you going to kill me now? - No, Pam, I'm gonna shoot you.
那是給猶太人的
That's for the Jews.
那些也是
Those too.
我抓到他了 怎麼樣 小夥子
Come on, boy!
傑瑪 讓我來這裡是有原因的 我不知道怎麼做 也不知道為什麼
Jemma put me here on purpose. I don't know how, I don't know why.
一定有充分的理由 該死 她一定很棒
There's gotta be a good reason. Shit, there's gotta be a great one.
看你搞丟了你的手機
Look, you lost your phone, little fella.
但她如今已經不在了
But she's gone.
我無法回去那麼遠的地方去救她
I can't get back far enough to reach her,
所以現在這些都不重要了
so none of this matters now.
整件事就剩下最後一部分了
There's only one real piece of business left.
復仇
Revenge.
這裡越來越熱了
Things are getting warm, now.
-你清算人員了嗎 -你指的是人員們吧 複數
- Did you eliminate the asset? - You mean assets. Plural.
-馬歇爾 -你好 佈雷特
- Marshall. - Hello, Brett.
別問我是誰 你很清楚的
Don't ask who this is, because you know exactly who it is.
-馬歇爾在哪兒 -是哪個 炸彈男嗎
- Where's Marshall? - Who's that? Bomb boy?
我叫他卡波姆什麼的
The one I call Kaboom?
那個他現在和我在一起吃燒烤呢
Well, he's at a big company barbeque at the moment.
我們還缺兩個人 你和那個下命令的混蛋
We're only missing two members: You and the shithead calling the shots
-你以為還有人在我之上嗎
You assume there's someone above me.
-你是條狗 必須得有人牽著
You're a lapdog, pal, so there's gotta be a leash.
我要那個掌控一切的人
I want who's holding it.
我要那個殺死傑瑪的人
I want who killed Jemma.
我猜是文托吧
I think it's Ventor.
-你知道我們在哪兒 山炮 -是的 我知道怎麼過去
- Well, you know where we are, hotshot. - Yeah, and I know how to get there.
我馬上就會見到你了狗娘養的
I'll see you in a minute, motherfucker.
大老闆可能會有大觀景台
I'm guessing the big boss man has a penthouse view,
但我不想再以那種卑鄙 不引人注意的方式死去
but I'm about sick to death of all the sneaky stealth behind the scenes bullshit.
我們來解決這一切吧 撞開前門
Let's go old-school and just kick the fucking front door down.
這可真是個好主意
That was a good plan.
我要把他的眼睛挖出來
I'm gonna gouge his eyes out.
報告
Hold!
後退
Fall back!
我一整天都能跟你玩的 混蛋（美國隊長梗）
I can do this all day, dick.
你好羅伊2號
Hello, Roy number 2!
再見羅伊2號
Goodbye, Roy number 2.
羅伊2號沒帶武器 我很肯定
Roy number 2 was unarmed and I'm positive
我要穿過這些傢伙不能拿著武器
I'm not getting a weapon past these guys.
先生
Sir.
哦 是的 當然 對不起
Oh, yeah, sorry.
拒絕訪問
Access denied.
這是我的錯
Oh, it's uh... It must be me.
你好嗎
Sir!
嗨羅伊
Hi, Roy.
我可不想跟布奇和聖丹斯玩了
So do I do a "Butch and Sundance" blaze of glory bit here?
絕不
Nah.
希望死最後一次
Never say die.
好詭異
That was weird.
操他媽的狗娘養的
You big motherfucker.
嗨 帥哥
Hello, handsome.
你把我的頭砍掉了幾十次
You cut my head off a couple of dozen times.
一定有人是勤奮的小蜜蜂
Someone's been the busiest little beaver.
你打算怎麼辦
What are you gonna do with that?
我在思考著把你搞死
I was thinking about fucking you up.
你還記得《征服者》裡的那個人 拿著劍
You remember in "Raiders", that asshole who was
在轉圈 然後想 他有多酷啊
twirling the sword around and around thinking he was all cool and shit?
因迪開槍打他 是因為他很生氣 沒耐心
Indy just shot him because he was exhausted and impatient
-這讓他很生氣
and just couldn't take the bullshit any more.
你還記得嗎 -是
- You remember that? - Yeah.
見鬼
Fuck!
也許你對刀劍殺人一無所知
Something you might not know about getting killed with a sword.
除了在第15次嘗試的時候
With the exception of attempt number 15.
被劍殺死比被槍殺更痛苦
Getting killed with a sword hurts worse than a gunshot.
還有一個關於劍的鮮為人知的事實
Another lesser known fact about swords.
當它們拔出來的時候 會痛很多倍的
They hurt a hell of a lot more coming out.
有趣的事實哈里森福特需要去大便
Fun fact: Harrison Ford had the shits,
所以他開搶打了那個人
and that's why he shot that guy.
我是觀音
I am Guan-Jin.
觀音完成任務
And Guan-Jin has done this.
我是觀音
I am Guan-Jin.
觀音完成任務
And Guan-Jin has done this.
我是觀音
I am Guan-Jin.
觀音完成任務
And Guan-Jin has done this.
我是觀音 任務完成
I'm Guan-Jin and I've done this.
這還不是最糟糕的部分
And this isn't even the worst part.
這才是文托
That's this. Ventor.
殺死傑瑪的人
The man who killed Jemma.
那個讓我死了一百五十次的白癡
The same bozo that's had me killed a hundred and fifty fucking times.
上尉 第一印象告訴我 你是一流的好手
Captain, as first impressions go this is truly stand-out stuff.
你對待這些一流的專業人士的方式
How you were able to despatch the elite level of
真讓人印象深刻
high speed professionals we threw at you is really remarkable.
不管結果如何 你都應該對你的努力感到滿意
You should be pleased with the effort, regardless of its outcome.
作為一個同樣收到過戰爭創傷的人
As someone who bears the same fraternal scars of battle I hope
我希望這種失敗 無論多麼苦澀 對你都是一種慰藉
that this defeat, however bitter, holds some solace.
他一定是把這些胡扯的東西都背下來了吧 每次都是一字不差的
He must that bullshit memorized, because it's word for word the same every time.
每一個在我眼前死去並安息的人，在這群人裡
All the men I've watched die and lain to rest, in their multitudes
我看到了一個共同點
I see a singularity.
在他們的眼中
It's in the eyes.
他們當時的情緒是一樣的
Their gaze is identical in this moment.
遺憾 悔恨
Remorse, regret.
我能做什麼 我沒做什麼
What could I have done? What didn't I do?
讓他們與我們一起流血 是我們所有的善意
All our best intentions left to bleed out with the rest of us.
但如果我們能讓世界重塑 並抹去我們犯過得錯誤呢
But what if we could remake our world whole and erase our mistakes?
如果改寫歷史的能力是真的呢
What if the ability to rewrite history was real?
-阿道夫希特勒 珍珠港 -等等 我好像從來沒活到過這一刻
- Adolf Hitler, Pearl Harbor. - Wait a minute, wait a minute,
所以這些扯淡都是新玩意
I never lived past this point, so all this crap is new.
你會把這個歐西裡斯的主軸這樣強大的工具交給誰呢？
In whose hands would you entrust a tool as powerful as the Osiris spindle?
我有你要的答案上尉
I have your answer, Captain.
我自己
Mine.
他深知人類苦難的重擔
A man brought to heel by the brunt of human misery,
像你一樣明白戰爭的恐怖
a man who understands, as you do, the horrors of war.
還有誰更適合來監督和實施這樣的工具呢
Who better to oversee and implement such a tool?
正是我本人
Exactly.
對於威爾斯博士 我很抱歉
I am sorry about Dr. Wells.
她帶著我們走了這麼遠 即是這是在她有所缺陷的思想的範疇內
She took us as far as her flawed ideology allowed her.
可愛的女孩
Sweet girl.
你來到這裡的目的 不過就是想要雙手沾滿鮮血罷了
Blood on your hands is what you wanted when you came here, Captain.
而現在你已經渾身浴血了
And blood is what you have.
只不過不是我的
Just not mine.
這真的很犀利 上面甚至沒留下血跡
That's really sharp. Not even any blood on it.
-這是把武士刀嗎 -武士刀嗎 那是日本的東西
- Is it a katana? - Katana? That's Japanese.
-這是一把中國劍 -別太較真
It's a Chinese sword. - Let's not make this about race.
就是把劍嘛
It's a sword.
佈雷特
Brett, um...
現在我知道三件事了 第一
I know three things now. One:
等下次我見到這傢伙我搞死他
I'm gonna fuck that guy up next time I see him.
第二 我被一種叫做歐西裡斯主軸的東西卡住了
Two: Whatever I'm stuck in is called the Osiris spindle.
第三 文托並不知道它開始運行了
And three: Ventor has no idea that it's working.
傑瑪不知怎的 把我捲進這一切 但為什麼呢
That somehow, Jemma put me inside this thing and started it up. But why?
她復活了她死去的丈夫歐西裡斯
She resurrected her dead husband, Osiris.
奧西裡斯成了死亡以及來世的
Osiris became the Lord of the Dead
統治者
and the afterlife.
我就是歐西裡斯
I'm Osiris.
傑瑪把我送進了主軸中 為了阻止他們 阻止文托
Jemma put me in the Spindle to stop them, to stop Ventor.
她需要我盡可能多的重複一切
She needs me to keep repeating this day until I do.
她擁有著信心
She had... She had faith.
該死 她還相信我
Son of a bitch, she still believed in me.
她知道我能打敗他們
She knew I could beat them.
你好 我想要學會用劍來戰鬥
Hi. I need to learn how to fight with a sword.
我不明你剛才說的是什麼
I have no idea what you just said.
我想要學習用劍戰鬥
I need to learn to fight with a sword.
你身上有些很迷人的東西我喜歡
There's something intriguing about you that I like.
我明早要坐飛機回去上海
I fly home to Shanghai in the morning.
-我只有一天時間 -一天可以做很多事
- I would only have a day. - I thinik we can get a lot done in a day.
我是初學者但我學得很快
I'm a beginner, but I'm a quick learner.
是那個揮舞它的人使它成為武器 羅伊
It is the one who wields it that makes it a weapon, Roy.
劍不僅是一把像車鑰匙的工具 更是身體的延伸
That sword is no more an extension of you than a set of car keys.
我受過一些訓練 而且我保持勤學苦練
I've had some training, but I'm willing to work hard.
在二流劍客手中劍不過是一塊
In lesser hands, the Jian blade is just a
劣質的硬鋼
flimsy piece of forged steel.
但在最堅定抓握和最敏銳眼神的掌控下
But within the most determined grip and under the keenest eyes
會成為一種致命的武器
it becomes a weapon of annihilation.
我有過一位非常厲害的老師 但我想學得更多
I've had a very good teacher, but I need to learn more.
嗨 帥哥
Hello, handsome.
你要放棄了嗎
Are you surrendering?
你不是真的想用劍來戰鬥 是吧
You're not really going to fight with a sword, are you?
我喜歡你的勇氣
I do like your confidence.
通常我是比較聰明的
Normally I'm a little more chatty.
我有件事要說
I do have one thing to say.
但得先等等
But I think it'll wait.
就這狗屎玩意兒 還假裝是鋼做的呢
Shit's about to get steel.
狗雜種
Motherfucker.
我想要說
I wanted to say was:
我叫羅伊 羅伊任務完成
I'm Roy. And Roy has done this.
哇嗚
Woah.
佈雷特
Brett...
我聞到了松餅的味道 你也能聞到嗎
I smell muffins. Do you smell muffins?
我要裂開了
I'll just walk it off.
而現在我什麼也看不到了
And now I'm blind.
-他看起來像一隻兩英尺高的獨角獸 -你這個狡猾的混蛋
- Looks like a four hundred pound unicorn. - You slippery son of a bitch.
-你要拿那把槍嗎 -我不想
- You gonna go for that gun? - I'm not.
-你知道為什麼嗎 -不知
- And do you know why? - No.
因為打你會讓我爽到爆
Because I'm gonna get great satisfaction from beating the shit out of you.
怎麼可能？
How?
你覺得呢
How do you think?
-主軸 她啟動了它 -她讓我進來的 夥計
- Spindle. She activated it. - Jemma. She put me inside, pal.
她把我送了進去 來阻止你
She put me inside to stop you,
然後你殺了她 因為她知道你要做什麼 文托
then you killed her because she knew what you were, Ventor.
想重塑整個世界的獨裁統治
A wannabe dictator, bent on a worldwide re-do.
該死的自?主義者
Fucking liberals.
在她放出她的洋娃娃瑪麗亞之前 她有費心地提到
Before she launched her little Hail-Mary, did she bother to mention
主軸反應如果太長時間 會摧毀整個星球嗎
that a spindle reaction, if maintained too long, can destroy the entire planet?
別擔心白癡 你是看不到世界終結時了
Don't worry, dickhead. If the world comes to an end, you won't be around to see it.
主軸賦予我們上帝的力量
The spindle gives us the power of God
來改變我們的整個世界不走向災難
to re-create our whole world, minus the tragedy.
-阿道夫希特勒 911 -別再扯淡了
- Adolf Hitler, 9/11... - Shut up with this bullshit speech.
過去就是過去 文托 這是為後人發明的東西
The past is the past, Ventor. It's designed to be left behind.
我們在生活中學習
We live and we learn from it.
這些話出自一個失蹤的丈夫和一個失敗的父親
And this from an absentee husband and a failed father.
我還以為你會更想要去做那些曾經未及之事
I would have thought you'd have more than a passing interest in re-doing things.
-比如你的兒子 -我兒子 怎麼了
- What about your son? - My son?
小喬 是吧
Young Joe, isn't it?
如果你跑這麼遠 來殺我
If you've come all this way to kill me,
誰去救他呢
well then who's saving him?
我從未想到喬會有危險
It never thought Joe would be in danger.
我沒有想到他會成為目標
I never thought in a million years that they'd ever target him.
如果他們傷害他的話 我要將文托
I'll kill Ventor and every one of those motherfuckers
和所有的雜碎碎屍萬段
a thousand times if they hurt that kid.
先生 先生 留在路障後面 先生 你不能過去
Sir, sir, behind the barricade, sir! You can't go that way, sir!
聽著夥計你得去路障後面
Pal, I need you behind the barricade. Pal!
我讓他死去多少次了
How many times have I let him die?
我的兒子
My son!
那是我的兒子我得去救他
It's my son! I need to save my son!
不
No!
在這
And there it is.
世界末日
The end of the world.
為什麼不會呢
Why not?
我的使命已經結束
Mine's already over.
我能感覺到不僅僅是死亡
I can feel it. Not just death,
我四分五裂 我的每一個部分
being unravelled, every part of me splits and splits again
都在一點點分崩離析
along with everything else.
我感到無能為力 唯一有能力改變一切的人卻已經死了
There's nowhere left to run and the one person who can help is dead.
我為她報了什麼仇
So what if I avenged her?
是我殺了她 不是文托 是我 我做的
I'm the one that killed her. Not Ventor, me. I did it.
我逃離了我們的感情 從而殺死了她
I killed her when I ran from relationship.
我沒有擔負起養育孩子的責任 我就已經殺了她
I killed her when I ran from raising our son. I killed her...
當我不給她回電話的時候
When I didn't call her back.
我就是她死亡的原因
I'm the reason she's gone.
我就是喬死亡的原因
I'm the reason Joe's gone.
我就是世界末日到來的原因
I am the reason the world ends.
有什麼意義呢
What the hell is the point?
我為什麼要去做嘗試呢
Why the hell should I even bother trying?
什麼都不重要了
Nothing will ever matter again.
你鍾愛的一切都已失去
Not when you've lost everything you've loved.
當你對人類的末日負有責任的時候
Not when you're responsible for the loss of all human life as we know it.
幹得好 你個混蛋
Nice job, asshole.
不能讓我至少睡一次好覺嗎
Can't you ever let me sleep in just once?
所以就是這樣
So this is it, then.
事情就是如此
This is it, huh?
你會後悔嗎 永遠 日復一日嗎
Are you just gonna feel sorry for yourself forever? Day in, day out?
你他媽的什麼都不做
You're not gonna do a god damn thing?
即使你什麼都做不了
Even if there isn't a god damn thing you can do?
不
No.
你是
You are.
你得做點什麼
You're gonna do something.
現在時間已經沒有任何意義了 不會有什麼再跟你作對
Time means nothing now. It's no longer counting against you.
-有人要搶我的車！
- I'm being car-jacked!
你也不會認識你兒子
You never got to know your son, so...
如果沒有遺漏下什麼的話
if that's all that's left,
這會比你應得的還要多
it's more than you ever deserved.
嗨 喬
Hey, Joe.
羅伊你在這裡做什麼發生了什麼事
Roy, what are you doing here? What happened to you?
我從營房裡跑出來了
I fell off a building.
翹課出來的嗎
Skipping school?
-我猜是吧 有電子競技比賽 -你怎麼知道的
- Let me guess: pop-up e-sports tournament. - How'd you know?
-我什麼都知道 -你是玩家嗎
- Where do you think I'm going? - You're a gamer?
我當然是玩家
Absolutely I'm a gamer.
我在X -BOX上看到了你 我就過來了
I knew you were on your X-Box every time I came over, but I didn't want to
我不會跟你媽媽說的 你知道嗎
blow it with your mom, you know.
我喜歡80年代的經典遊戲
I'm into like the old eighties vintage side-scroller games
-就像巨獸和雙龍那種 -街頭霸王
- like Altered Beast and Double Dragon. - Street Fighter?
我最喜歡這個了
It's my favourite.
-我也是 -是嗎 -是啊
- Mine too. - Yeah?
-但我也喜歡新遊戲 -嘿 羅伊
- I like the new stuff, too, though... - Hey, Roy,
我翹課出來 媽媽會生氣嗎
do you think mom will be pissed that I bailed on school.
你知道嗎 她會很生氣的
You know what? She'll be pissed.
但我會替你打掩護的好嗎
But I'm gonna cover for you, okay?
-好 -但不要再翹課了 好嗎 -好
- But no more skipping school, okay? - Cool.
-一言為定嗎 -當然
- Cool? - Cool.
那我們就去玩街頭霸王吧
So let's go play some Street Fighter.
-你死定了 -你死定了
- You're gonna die. - No, you're gonna die.
你會被幹死輸掉的
You're gonna die and fail...
我搞砸了但我還活
Oh, my bad! But I'm still alive!
這個遊戲太老了 叫什麼名字來 格拉卡嗎
This game is so old! What's it called? Glaca?
加拉加加拉加
- This game's broken. - Galaga. Galaga.
重擊面門
Right in the face!
-反正我贏了 -當然
- I still won. - I got it!
直接擊倒
K.O.
-你贏了 -你為什麼這麼喜歡這個遊戲
- You win! - Why do you like this game so much?
有很多人在追你 你必須殺掉他們
Well, there's a lot of people that chase you and you get to kill them.
-那是一次力量提升 -超級芝麻菜
- That was a power boost. - Oh, that was Aku- Arugula?
-是芝麻菜嗎 -阿魯根
- Was that the Arugula? - Hadouken!
阿魯根再來
Haru-gen again!
阿魯根
Haru-gen!
-你是怎麼 -你藏了
- How did you ...? - You win!
-這變得越來越難了 -對 抓住那個女孩 那個女孩
- This is where it it gets hard. - Yeah, get the girl. Get the girl.
你知道嗎 我來給你展示怎麼玩
You know what? Let me show you how its done.
那個人不斷地出現
Man, these guys keep coming.
我不知道
You have no idea.
-我不怕他們 -對一個不會騎自行車的人來說 你已經很聰明了
For a kid who doesn't go to school that much you're pretty smart.
我有我自己的玩法
I have my ways.
你又打敗我了
You beat me again.
我也是個大師啦
Of course, because I'm the master.
我想回到過去 我曾經搞砸了的那些年
All the years of this that I missed.
他擁有傑瑪的外表
He has Jemma's looks,
她的敏銳性 幽默感
her smarts, her sense of humor.
謝天謝地
Thank God.
然後我看到他笑了我看到了我自己
Then I see that kid laugh and I see myself.
只是一瞬間
Just a flash.
就像我在看我自己的笑臉
I see my own face smiling back at me
這讓我心碎
it breaks my heart.
我可以永遠這樣下去 我就是這麼想的
I could do forever, and I just might.
下去我就是這麼想的
我可以永遠這樣下去 我就是這麼想的
我們過了超過十幾次這樣的日子
We've ended this day just like this over a dozen times now.
永遠不會變老
It never gets old.
我喜歡在一切終結時 他睡著的樣子
I like that he's sound asleep when it all ends.
甚至都不會有一絲顫抖
I like that he never stirs once.
我想像以前那樣告訴他 我是他的父親 但是我害怕
I want to tell him that I'm his father, like I did before, but I'm scared.
害怕他不會再像那樣看著我
I'm scared he won't look at me that way again.
害怕無法再從他的眼睛裡看到我想看到的東西
I won't see what I saw in his eyes.
所以我什麼也沒有說
So I say nothing.
有朝一日 我想要有一艘船 載著媽媽
I want to get a boat one day. Take mom out in it.
她其實哪兒也不想去
She never gets out at all.
我想要租一艘
I just wish I could rent one.
-我該租一艘嗎 -一艘船嗎
- Could we rent one? - A boat?
對 帶媽媽出海
Yeah. Take mom out in it.
-為什麼不呢 -什麼時候
- I don't see why not. - When?
隨時我們可以
Whenever, I... We could...
我想告訴他 這個週末 我們就可以
This is when I tell him we can do it this weekend.
然後給媽媽留言 說我們要去航海了
Then he send his mom a text telling her that we're all going sailing.
這種情況經常發生
This is what usually happens.
喬
Joey...
-你知道 你媽媽 -怎麼
- You know, your mom... - Yeah?
-你知道你媽媽在做什麼嗎 -歐西裡斯的主軸
- Do you know what your mom is working on? - The Osiris spindle?
歐西裡斯主軸
Osiris spindle.
你知道這是做什麼的嗎
You know what that does?
她不能講 說是頂級機密什麼的
She can't talk about it because it's like super secret and whatever.
但我聽她說過 這個可以毀滅一切
But I overheard her say it could wipe out everything,
我是說全世界 如果他們稍不小心的話
like the world, I guess, if they weren't careful.
你相信嗎
Do you believe that?
是我信
Yeah, I do.
我希望我不信
I wish I didn't.
你媽媽信任我而我讓她失望了
Your mom trusted me with something and I let her down.
你什麼意思
What do you mean?
-昨晚 你媽媽 -她沒回家
- Last night, your mom... - She didn't come home.
-我知道 -她有新男朋友了嗎
- I know. - Does she have a new boyfriend?
不不是新男朋友
No. There's no new boyfriend.
她知道我翹課了嗎
Did she know I was ditching school?
-看上去 你一直在跟著我 -是 不過
- It felt like you were following me. - Yeah, I was,
倒不是這個原因
but not for that reason.
-那為什麼 -我不知道
- Why then? - I don't know.
我看見你了 我就想和你聊聊 我們之前沒怎麼交流過
I saw you and I wanted to talk to you. Catch up, we haven't spoken to each other.
你為什麼覺得我在跟著你
Why did you think I was following you?
因為媽媽早上說過些事情
Just something Mom said this morning.
?等等 什麼 -在電話上 很奇怪
- Wait, what? - On the phone. It was weird.
她說如果我遇到了什麼麻煩 就去找你
She said if I got into any trouble, that I should find you.
喬 是媽媽 快接電話 拜託
Joe, it's Mom. Pick up the phone, please.
-我不明白她在說些什麼 -你今天跟你媽媽說過話嗎
- I didn't know what she was talking about. - You spoke to mom today?
當今天發生一些奇怪的事情時 我想要你打電話給羅伊 好嗎
If anything strange happens, I want you to call Roy, okay?
-那是幾點 -我不知道
- What time? - I don't know, um...
我會把他的電話號碼發給你 但現在快給我回電話 再見寶貝
I'm gonna text you his number, but call me back. Bye baby.
嘿 夥計 讓我看看你的手機
Hey bud, let me see your phone.
我醒來的時候 她還活著
She was still alive when I woke up.
文托還沒有殺她
Ventor hadn't killed her.
她還沒有死
She wasn't dead yet.
別擔心 兒子 我會回來找你的
Don't worry, son. I'll come back for you.
我會回來找你們兩個的
I'm coming back for both of you.
你要殺死她
You killed her.
-你他媽的怎麼到這兒來的 -她在哪兒 她在哪兒
- How the hell did you get in here? - Where is she? Where is she?!
-你想要毀掉證據嗎 -我想要搞清楚 她做了什麼
- You trying to erase the evidence? - Trying to figure out what she was doing.
-她打算如何運行 -閉嘴 佈雷特
- How she was able to initiate the spindle... - Shut your mouth, Brett!
繼續繼續
Continue. Continue!
我們沒有搞清楚 歐西裡斯的主軸 是如何工作的
We can't get the Osiris spindle to function.
她引發的連鎖反應 我們無法控制
Whatever she did started a chain reaction that we can't control.
不知何故 她對它進行了破壞 現在已無法匹配
She sabotaged it somehow and it's not responding.
狗娘養的
You son of a bitch.
主軸在工作
The spindle is working.
是你她讓你變成了缺失的部分
It's you. She made you the missing mass.
否則你怎麼會進入設備呢
Otherwise, how could you have broken into this facility?
多少
How...
你嘗試了多少次了
How many times have you done this?
-很多次了 -成功了
- A lot. - It works.
我醒來後 她至少還活了14分鐘
She was alive at least 14 minutes after I woke up.
我有時間去救她
I have time to save her.
好吧 就這麼做
Okay. Lets do this.
只有傑瑪能阻止這一切
Jemma is the only one who can stop this,
我還有14分鐘去找她
and you have at least 14 minutes to reach her.
去他媽的開始吧
What the hell. Here we go.
那個混蛋剛剛跳了出來
The fuckin' asshole just jumped.
走啊混蛋快走啊
Fly, motherfucker.
我只有十二分半鐘 給我盡可能快的飛
I've got twelve and a half minutes. Make this thing go faster.
快點
Move!
飛得不錯白癡
Nice flying, dick.
現土	要一場真正的大殲滅
I want the big knock down, drag out now...
多尼布魯克 皇家戰役
A Donnybrook. The Battle Royale.
他們過來了 而我可以群滅他們不浪費一點時間
Bring 'em all on, every last one of 'em so I can light 'em up and lay waste...
為了這一幕我等了很久
Because I've been waiting for this for a long fucking time.
不需太久
Maybe too long.
所以你知道 我可沒一整天時間陪他們玩
I mean, you know, I don't have all day.
嘿 佈雷特
Hey, Brett!
你來救我了
You came for me.
你做到了
You did it.
你來救我了
You came for me.
-你嘗試了多少次 -就一次
- How many times did it take? - Just one.
我時間不多快點
We don't have much time. Come on.
我不能直接告訴你 他們在監視著我
I couldn't tell you. They were watching me.
我不得不整晚潛入實驗室
I had to sneak around the lab all night.
我只好把書帶給你了
I barely got that book to you.
剛剛夠用
It was just enough.
我覺得文託派了什麼人 去找喬了
I think Ventor sent men after Joe.
一個人也沒落下 傑瑪 都幹掉了
There's no one left. They're all gone, Jemma.
喬是安全的
Joe's fine.
他為了電子遊戲逃了學 但他沒事的
He's skipping school for a gamer con, but he's okay.
你是怎麼知道的
How do you know that?
他喜歡他們班一個叫卡米爾的女孩
He's got a crush on a girl in his class named Camille.
他和她坐同一輛公車上學
He showed her all the bus routes to school
但他不敢約她出去玩
but he's afraid to ask her to be his girl.
幾周前 他和他的朋友懷亞特為了參加
He and his friend Wyatt, they lied about their age
彩彈錦標賽而謊報了自己的年齡
a couple of weeks ago to enter a paintball tournament.
你還記得他脖子上的瘀傷嗎
You asked him about a welt on his neck.
他說他那裡被蟲子咬了
He said he got it from a bug bite.
他上個月玩滑板時摔斷了他手腕
He fractured his wrist last month skateboarding
現在那裡能發出相當奇怪的聲音 -當然
- and now it makes this weird clicking sound. - Clicking
他喜歡狗 尤其是哈巴狗
He loves dogs, especially pugs
他覺得你們應該養一隻
and he thinks you two should rescue one.
大約一年前他用水彩畫了
梵古的星空之夜給你 祝你生日快樂
He did a watercolor version of Van Gogh's 'Starry Night' about a year ago
因為他知道 那是你最喜歡的畫
for your birthday because he knew it was your favourite painting.
他覺得媽媽工作太多 微笑太少
He thinks mom works too much and doesn't smile enough
但這個男孩真的非常愛你
But that boy loves you so much.
我怎樣才能終止這玩意兒 傑瑪
How do I stop this, Jemma?
這不是終止 羅伊 是重置
It's not about stopping, Roy. It's about restarting.
我用你的DNA作了主軸內缺失的部分
I made your dimensions, your DNA specific to the missing mass within the spindle.
-這是什麼意思
What does that mean?
-你必須進入主軸的核心
It means you have to enter the Spindle's core, then theoretically
接著 理論上 時空將會連續重置並恢復到正常
the time-space continuum should reset and resume.
-理論上？ -我不知道
- Theoretically? - I don't know.
說實話我不知道羅伊
I honestly don't, Roy.
整件事都是匆忙中決定的 我只是想阻止文托
This whole thing's so cobbled together. I was just trying to stop Ventor.
我甚至都不知道 它是否會有效 直到你出現
I didn't even know it worked until you showed up.
我只記得 我昨晚剛剛見過你
You have to remember, I just saw you yesterday.
而我已經很久都沒見過你了
And I haven't seen you in forever.
我不知道還能做什麼還能去哪裡
I didn't know what else to do, where else to turn.
我知道你是誰
I just knew the man you were.
我知道你是什麼樣的人
I know the man you are.
但我不知道如果你去了機器裡面你會怎麼樣
But I don't know what will happen to you if you go in there.
但我知道如果我不去的話會發生什麼
But I know what happens if I don't.
你見過了世界的終結
You saw it? The end of the world?
-對 -是什麼樣子
- Yeah. - What was it like?
它比你能想像到最不可思議的還要糟糕一百萬倍
It was everything you imagine it to be, only a million times worse.
如果我走進這個機器 那什麼都會正常嗎
Will it go forward? If I walk through this thing
它會重置嗎 你和喬是不是就安全了
Is it gonna reset? Are you and Joe gonna be safe?
如果你讓你的部分品質回歸到機器的核心 它就會重置
If you return your mass to the core, it should.
但有可能會失敗
You may not make it.
你可能會不復存在
You may cease to be.
那
Well then...
親我一下 說你愛我
Give me a kiss and tell me you love me.
我愛你
I love you.
-等著我 好嗎 -我會的
- Wait for me, huh? - I will.
媽了個巴子 老子要上了
What the hell. Here we go.